オケアノス
Ôkeanos.
But what's with this change of heart?
しかしまた どういう風の吹き回しだ
We're heading out to town?
町に出ようとは
Nothing. I just want a change of pace.
別に ただの気分転換だよ
Weren't you constantly whining about wanting to visit the busy areas?
お前だって盛り場を出歩きたいって ずっとごねてたじゃないか
The joy of visiting markets in foreign lands is every bit as great as the joy of battle.
異郷の市場をひやかす愉しみは
戦の興奮に勝るとも劣らぬからな
I feel really bad for the nations that got invaded for a reason like that.
そんな理由で戦争ふっかけられた国は 本当に気の毒だよな
What's up, boy? You say it like you actually saw it happen.
何だ坊主 そのまるで見てきたかのような言いぐさは
Don't worry about it.
いいんだよ こっちの話だ
Utw
Presents
Kurikaesu sekai nando te wo nobashitara
繰り返す世界 何度手を伸ばしたら
How many times must I reach my hand out to this repeating world
Kurikaesu sekai nando te wo nobashitara
繰り返す世界 何度手を伸ばしたら
How many times must I reach my hand out to this repeating world
Hakanai namida wa kuroi kokoro tokasu no
儚い涙は黒い心溶かすの？
For the fleeting tears to soften my black heart?
Hakanai namida wa kuroi kokoro tokasu no
儚い涙は黒い心溶かすの？
For the fleeting tears to soften my black heart?
Mebaedashita omoi ga mune ni hibiita nara
芽生え出した思いが胸に響いたなら
If these awakened feelings resonated in my heart
Mebaedashita omoi ga mune ni hibiita nara
芽生え出した思いが胸に響いたなら
If these awakened feelings resonated in my heart
Kimi no tonari de zutto kawarazu mamoru darou
君の隣でずっと変わらず護るだろう
I'd stand guard beside you forever and ever
Kimi no tonari de zutto kawarazu mamoru darou
君の隣でずっと変わらず護るだろう
I'd stand guard beside you forever and ever
Ochita kibou wo hirotte
堕ちた希望を拾って
If I could pick up these fallen hopes
Ochita kibou wo hirotte
堕ちた希望を拾って
If I could pick up these fallen hopes
Asu ni tsunaide yukeba
明日に繋いでゆけば
And link them on to tomorrow
Asu ni tsunaide yukeba
明日に繋いでゆけば
And link them on to tomorrow
Karamatta ibitsu na negai datte hodokeru
絡まった歪な願いだってほどける
Even these entwined, twisted wishes will come apart
Karamatta ibitsu na negai datte hodokeru
絡まった歪な願いだってほどける
Even these entwined, twisted wishes will come apart
Hikari wo kazashite tamerai wo keshita
光をかざして躊躇いを消した
I've held up the light and erased my hesitation
Hikari wo kazashite tamerai wo keshita
光をかざして躊躇いを消した
I've held up the light and erased my hesitation
Agetakatta no wa mirai de
あげたかったのは未来で
What I wanted to give you is in the future
Agetakatta no wa mirai de
あげたかったのは未来で
What I wanted to give you is in the future
Naiteru yoru daita mama
泣いてる夜抱いたまま
Crying and embracing the night
Naiteru yoru daita mama
泣いてる夜抱いたまま
Crying and embracing the night
Nageki wo sakende
嘆きを叫んで
Screaming its grief out loud
Nageki wo sakende
嘆きを叫んで
Screaming its grief out loud
Fumiireta ashi wo tooku no risou ga
踏み入れた足を遠くの理想が
The distant ideals gently heal
Fumiireta ashi wo tooku no risou ga
踏み入れた足を遠くの理想が
The distant ideals gently heal
Sotto iyashite yuku
そっと癒してゆく
These legs that've stepped forward
Sotto iyashite yuku
そっと癒してゆく
These legs that've stepped forward
Tashika na kizuna wo tsuyoku nigirisusumou
確かな絆を強く握り進もう
I'll hold on tight to these definite bonds as I advance
Tashika na kizuna wo tsuyoku nigirisusumou
確かな絆を強く握り進もう
I'll hold on tight to these definite bonds as I advance
Dokomade mo
どこまでも
No matter where I go
Dokomade mo
どこまでも
No matter where I go
Kegarekitta kiseki wo se ni
穢れきった奇跡を背に
I'll shoulder these tainted miracles
Kegarekitta kiseki wo se ni
穢れきった奇跡を背に
I'll shoulder these tainted miracles
This is horrible...
ヒデエ
It's too much!
あんまりだ
We worked so hard to create all this art...
精魂込めて俺達が仕上げてきたアートが 酷すぎる
How could they?!
こんな これが人間のやることかようー
How...
How could anyone do this and still call themselves human?!
龍之介
Ryuunosuke.
Only a very select few can comprehend true beauty and harmony.
本当の美と調和というものを理解できるのは
ごく一握りの人間だけなのです
To the vast majority of philistines,
beauty is simply something to destroy.
むしろ大方の俗物にとって
美とは破壊の対象にしかなり得ないものなのです
That is why we mustn't become
excessively attached to our creations.
なればこそ　被造物に過度の愛着を抱くのは禁物だ
All things that are given form are fated to break one day.
ひとたび形を与えられた物は　いずれ壊れゆく運命にあるのです
Instead, we creators should find joy in the process of creation itself.
むしろ我々創造者は　創作の過程にこそ喜びを懐くべきなのです
So we create just as much as they break?
壊れたぶんだけ　また造りゃあいいってこと
その通り
Precisely!
いつもながら龍之介　その端的なる理解は貴方の美徳ですよ
As always, Ryuunosuke, your frank understanding is your virtue.
俺たち あんまり楽しみすぎたせいで
Maybe we had too much fun...
...so God punished us.
もしかして 罰が当たったのかなあ
I'll tell you this, Ryuunosuke.
これだけは言っておきますよ 龍之介
神は決して人間を罰しない ただ玩弄するだけです
God never punishes humans!
He simply toys with them.
M-Mister?
だ 旦那
I once committed greater atrocities and
blasphemies than had ever been done on this Earth.
かつて私は およそ地上にて具現しうる限りの悪逆と涜神を積み重ねた
だが 殺せども穢せども この身に下るはずの神罰はなく
But no matter how much I murdered
and defiled, no divine punishment came!
気がつけば邪悪の探求は八年に及んで放任され 看過され続けた
Next thing I knew, my quest for evil
had been ignored for eight whole years.
結局 最後に私を滅ぼしたのは神ではなく
In the end, it was not God who destroyed me, but the self-interests of humans just like me.
私と同じ人間どもの欲得でした
教会と国王が断罪の名目で私を処刑したのは
The church and the king convicted and executed me simply because they coveted my wealth and land!
我が手中にあった富と領土を簒奪したいがためだった
我が背徳に歯止めをかけたのは 裁きなどとは程遠い
What brought an end to my evil deeds wasn't judgment or anything like it.
ただの略奪だったのですよ
It was simply theft!
でも 旦那
But, Mister...
それでも 神様はいるんだろ
God still exists, right?
何故信仰もなく奇跡も知らぬ貴方がそのように思うのです
You are faithless and never witnessed a miracle. Why would you think that?
Because the world appears to be boring...
だってこの世は 退屈だらけなようでいて
だけど　探せば探すほど 面白可笑しいことが多すぎる
But you just have to look to find all kinds of crazy stuff!
I've always thought this.
昔から思ってたよ
こんなにも愉快なことが仕込まれまくってる世界ってのは
A world filled with so many wonderful things could never have come about by chance.
出来すぎてるぐらいな代物だって
いざ本気で楽しもうと思ったら
Once you decide to enjoy it for real, you'll
find no better entertainment in this world!
この世界に勝るほどのエンターテインメントはねえよ
There's got to be an entertainer out there
who's writing a saga about five billion people.
きっと登場人物五十億人の大河小説を書いてるエンターテイナーがいるんだ
そんなヤツについて語ろうと思ったら
If you wanted to describe somebody like that...
こりゃあもう 神様としか呼びようがねえ
God is the only thing you could call him!
Then, Ryuunosuke, do you think God loves humans?
では龍之介 はたして神は人間を愛していると思いますか
そりゃあもう ぞっこんに
He's head over heels!
He couldn't possibly write the saga of this world continuously and restlessly without love!
この世界のシナリオを ずっと休まず書き続けてるんだとしたら
そりゃ愛がなきゃやってられねぇでしょ
きっともうノリノリで書いてんだと思うよ
I'm sure he has loads of fun writing it, enjoying his own work all the while.
自分で自分の作品を楽しみながら
神様は勇気とか希望とかいった人間賛歌が大好きだし
God loves human virtues like courage and hope,
それと同じぐらいに血飛沫やら悲鳴やら絶望だって大好きなのさ
but he loves screams, blood, and despair just as much!
If he didn't, there's no way fresh intestines could be so colorful!
でなけりゃあ 生き物のハラワタがあんなにも色鮮やかなわけがない
だから旦那 きっとこの世界は神様の愛に満ちてるよ
That's why I'm sure the world is filled with God's love!
In an era where people no longer believe
and the state has abandoned God's will...
もはや民草に信心はなく 為政もまた神意を捨てたこの時代に
I had no idea a faith as new and
invigorating as yours could result!
まさかこんなにも新しく瑞々しい信仰が芽吹いていようとは
心服しました 龍之介
You have my admiration, Ryuunosuke, my Master!
我がマスターよ
Come on, don't make me blush!
いやそんな 照れくさいって
But wouldn't my blasphemies simply be a
farce according to your religious viewpoint?
しかし 貴方の宗教観に依るならば
我が涜神も茶番にすぎないのでしょうか
Nah.
いやさ 汚れ役だってきちっと引き受けて笑いを取るのが
It takes the best entertainers to get
smiles out of playing the villain, right?
一流のエンターテイナーってもんでしょ
If you ask me, I bet God just loves playing along with your antics!
旦那の容赦ないツッコミには
きっと神様も大喜びでボケを返してくれると思うけど
涜神も 礼賛も
So you're saying that both blasphemy
and praise are forms of worship to you?!
貴方にとっては等しく同じ崇拝であると仰せか
龍之介 まったく貴方という人は深遠な哲学をお持ちだ
Ryuunosuke!
You truly are the bearer of a deep and profound philosophy!
A God who makes puppets of all men for
his sport and is just another clown himself...
あまねく万人を愛玩人形とする神が
自身もまた道化とは
なるほど
I see.
ならばその悪辣な趣向も頷ける
Then his vicious ways make sense.
Very well.
宜しい
Then we'll have to stain the garden of God
with the brilliant colors of despair and terror.
ならば ひときわ色鮮やかな絶望と慟哭で
神の庭を染め上げてやろうではないですか
We'll have to show the director in heaven that he's
not the only one who knows what entertainment is!
娯楽の何たるかを心得ているのは神だけではないということを
天上の演出家に知らしめてやらねば
Are we gonna do something awesome again, Mister?
何かまたスゲェことやるんだね 旦那
Cool! Cool!
クール クール
All right, I'll be in this bookstore for a while.
じゃあ　ボクは　しばらくこの本屋にいるから
うむ
You can do anything you want except leave this arcade.
取り敢えずオマエは何やっててもいいけど　このアーケードからは絶対に出るな
もし万が一ボクが襲われたら　オマエだって一巻の終わりなんだからな
In the event I'm attacked, it's all over for you too, got it?
うむ　うむ
No conquering.
征服するなよ　略奪するなよ
No plundering.
Huh?
「えっ」じゃねぇぇよッ
"Huh"? What do you mean, "huh"?!
もうッ
No shoplifting, and no eating without paying!
万引きも　無銭飲食も　一切ナシだ
欲しいものがあったらきちんと金を払え
If you want something, pay for it with money!
それとも令呪で言い聞かせないと判らないか
Or do I have to use a Command Spell to make you listen?
はっはっは　何を無粋な
No need to be rude.
マケドニアの礼儀作法はどこの宮廷でも文明人として通用したぞ
Macedonian etiquette passed for civility in palaces everywhere.
Well, I'll see you later, boy.
では坊主　また後でな
大王は勝ち取った占領地での支配も利権も 全て地元の豪族に放り投げ
The king gave dominion and the power to tax to
the local nobles and took his armies further east.
自らは軍を引き連れてさらに東へと去って行った
夢で見た通りだ
Just like what I saw in my dream.
アイツはただ 最果ての海に
He just wanted to reach the sea at the world's edge...
Did he continue his campaign so he could see Ôkeanos?
オケアノスに辿り着きたいがために 遠征を続けたのか
おい 坊主 何処だ
Hey, boy! Where are you?
There you are.
You're so small that it's impossible to see you in between the bookshelves.
そうチビっこいと本棚の間にいたんじゃ全然見えんなあ
探すのに苦労したわい
Finding you was tough.
People are normally smaller than bookshelves, idiot.
普通の人間は本棚より小さいんだ 馬鹿
So what did you buy?
で 何買ってきたんだよ
Check this out.
Game:  Admirable War Tactics
ほれ なんと「アドミラブル大戦略」は本日発売であったのだ
Admirable War Tactics came out today!
初回限定版だ
And I got the first press limited edition!
余のラックはやっぱり伊達ではないな
My Luck must be pretty high!
あのな
You know, there's no point in buying the game if you don't have the console for it.
そういうものはソフトだけ買ったって
肝心のゲーム機はないとは
Game:  Admirable War Tactics
抜かりはない
No problems there.
Come on, boy.
さあ坊主 帰ったらさっそく対戦プレイだ
We're playing VS mode when we get back.
I even bought two controllers!
パッドも二つ買ってきたからな
I'm not interested in low-class entertainment like that.
僕はな そういう下賤で低俗な遊戯には興味ないんだよ
Man, why do you keep restricting your own view of the world?
もう なんで貴様はそうやって好きこのんで自分の世界を狭めるかなあ
ちったあ楽しいことを探そうとは思わんのか
Don't you ever want to try anything fun?
Shut up.
うるさいな
If I have time to waste, I'd rather spend it on a search for Truth.
余計なことに興味を割くぐらいなら
真理の探究に専念するのが
So what were you looking for here, then?
んで そういう貴様が興味を持っていたのは
This book?
この本か
Whoa there, this is a book about me!
ておい こりゃ余の伝記ではないか
You're a weird guy.
おかしなヤツだな
I'm right here. You could've just asked me if you wanted to know something.
当の本人が目の前にいるんだから
直に何なりと訊けば良いではないか
Sure, I'll ask!
訊いてやる 訊いてやるよ
I'll ask you, then!
History says you were really short.
お前 歴史だとすっげえチビだったってことになってるぞ
それがどうしてそんな馬鹿でかい図体で現界してるんだよ
So why have you materialized with such a huge body?
余が矮躯とな
It says I'm short?
Looks like you really can't trust books written by someone you don't know.
やはり 何処の誰とも知れんヤツが書き留めたものなんぞ
当てにならんもんだわい
違ってるなら 違ってるで怒らないのかよ
You're not mad that it's wrong?
別に気にすることもないが
It doesn't really bother me, no.
Is that strange?
変か
Aren't people in power, no matter the era, desperate to leave their name in history?
いつの時代だって 権力者ってのは
自分の名前を後世に遺そうと思って躍起になるもんだろ
そりゃまあ 史実に名を刻むというのも
I suppose having your name recorded in
the history books is a form of immortality.
ある種の不死性ではあろうがな
But if it's just my name and nothing else that got passed down
for two thousand years, I'd rather have even a hundredth of that...
そんな風に本の中の名前ばっかり二千年も永らえるぐらいなら
せめてその百分の一でいい
現身の寿命が欲しかったわい
...added to my life.
じゃ 三十そこそこで死んだっていうのは
Then is it true that you died in your early thirties?
Yes, that's right.
ほう そりゃあ合っとるな
Mister!
旦那
Show us something that'll shock even God!
神様もびっくりなすっげえツッコミ頼んだぜ
旦那
Mister!
Look forward to it, Ryuunosuke!
ご期待あれ 龍之介
最高のクールをご覧にいれましょう
I'll give you the greatest "Cool!" you've ever seen!
Seriously?
マジ
楽しみにしてるからさ
I can't wait!
Ph'nglui mglw'nafh wgah'nagl fhtagn.
Something awesome's gonna happen!
今からすっげえ面しれえことが始まるんだ
Why are you so quiet?
なあにを黙り込んどるのだ
Nothing.
別に
I was just thinking about how boring you are.
お前のこと つまんないなって思っただけだ
What?
なあんだ
So you were bored after all.
やっぱり退屈しとるんじゃないか
Then stop whining and play this game with me.
だったら意地張らずにこのゲームを
That's not it!
違う
Even if I get the Grail for a Servant like you who's practically guaranteed to win...
お前みたいな 勝って当然のサーヴァントに聖杯を獲らせたって
I couldn't take pride in that at all.
僕には何の自慢にもならない
It would've been way more rewarding if I'd contracted with Assassin!
いっそアサシンとでも契約してた方が
まだやり甲斐があったってもんだ
I don't know if that would've worked.
そりゃ無茶だったんじゃないかのう
I think you'd be dead.
たぶん死んでるぞ 貴様
That's fine!
いいんだよ 僕は僕の戦いで死ぬんなら文句ない
I have no problems with dying in my own battle!
That's why I joined the Grail War!
そう思って僕は聖杯戦争に加わったんだ
Yet...
それが
I don't know what to tell you.
そんなこと言われてもなあ
If your wish for the Grail was something that impressed me, I wouldn't mind obeying you.
貴様が聖杯に託す願いが 余を魅せるほどの大望であったなら
この征服王とて貴様の差配に従うのも吝かではなかったが
如何せん 背丈を伸ばしたいってだけが悲願じゃなあ
But since you just want to use it to get taller...
勝手に決めるなよ それ
Don't just assume things!
You don't need to be in such a hurry.
そんなに焦らんでも良かろうて
なにもこの聖杯戦争が貴様にとって人生最大の見せ場ってわけじゃなかろう
It's not like the Grail War'll be the
most important event of your life-
What?!
何を
When you someday find a way of life that you can be truly proud of, you'll be forced into your own battle whether you like it or not.
いずれ貴様が真に尊いと誇れる生き様を見出したら
その時には嫌が応にも自分のための戦いを挑まなければならなくなる
己の戦場を求めるのは そうなってからでも遅くはない
You can search for your battlefield then.
I can't be the only one who's not satisfied with this contract.
この契約に納得できないのは なにも僕だけじゃないだろう
I'm sure you don't like it either!
お前だって不満なんだろうが
Having a Master as pathetic as me.
こんな僕がマスターだなんて
You'd be able to win a lot easier if you made a
contract with a more competent Master, right?
本当はもっと違うマスターと契約してれば
よっぽど簡単に勝てたんだろ
I wonder about that.
そうさなあ
Look at this, boy.
ほれ坊主 見てみよ
余が立ち向かっている敵の姿を
This is the enemy I'm fighting.
ここに描かれた敵の隣に 我らの姿を描き込んでみよ
Try to draw the two of us next to the enemy.
So that we can compare you and me.
余と貴様と 二人並べて比べられるように
That's...
そんなのは
...impossible, right?
無理であろう
Against the enemy we're about to fight, you and I are the same.
これより立ち向かう敵を前にしては
貴様も余も同じ 極小の点でしかない
Just tiny little dots.
What point is there in comparing how big we are?
そんな二人の背比べなんぞに何の意味がある
But that's exactly why I am excited!
だからこそ 余は滾る
It doesn't matter how weak or small you are.
至弱 極小 多いに結構
この芥子粒に劣る身をもって
With a body not even the size of a dot, I will someday surpass the world.
いつか世界を凌駕せんと大望を懐く
The excitement in my chest is what causes the King of Conquerors' heart to beat!
この胸の高鳴り これこそが征服王たる心臓の鼓動よ
要するに
So you're basically saying your Master doesn't matter, right?
マスターなんてどうでもいいって言いたいんだな
僕がどんなに弱かろうと そもそもお前にとっては問題にもならないんだな
No matter how weak I am, it won't pose you any problems.
Where'd that come from?
なんでそうなるんだ おい
貴様のそういう卑屈さこそが 即ち覇道の兆しなのだぞ
The inferiority you feel is actually the quality of a king.
You may grumble a lot, but you know how small you are.
貴様は四の五の言いつつも 結局は己の小ささを判っとる
And yet, you'll still struggle to reach
heights greater than you can imagine.
それを知った上でなお
分を弁えぬ高みを目指そうと足掻いておるのだからな
That's not a compliment.
それ 褒めてないぞ
You're making fun of me.
馬鹿にしてるぞ
That's right, boy.
そうとも 坊主
You're a hopeless idiot.
貴様は筋金入りの馬鹿だ
Your desires lie beyond yourself.
貴様の欲望は己の埒外を向いている
"Glory lies beyond the horizon", after all.
「彼方にこそ栄え在り（ト·フィロティモ）」といってな
In the world I lived in, that was the most basic rule of life.
余の生きた世界では それが人生の基本則だったのだ
Is that why you kept heading east like an idiot?
だから馬鹿みたいにひたすら東へ遠征を続けたのかよ
Yes. That's right.
あ そうだ
I wanted to see Ôkeanos with my own eyes.
この目でオケアノスを見たくてな
But my dream didn't come true.
だが結局 夢は叶わなかったわい
He didn't see that sea?
あの海を見ていない
オケアノスは 今なお余の目指す場所
Ôkeanos remains the place I strive for.
見果てぬ夢よ
It's an endless dream.
That sea is an imagined scenery Rider holds in his heart.
あの海はライダーが胸に懐いてきた こころの景色なんだ
Laugh if you want.
笑うがいい
I'm just another idiot who dreams the same dream even after two thousand years.
2千年のときが経とうと未だ同じ夢を懐き続けている
余もまた大馬鹿者だ
So, boy.
だからな 坊主
A contract with an idiot like you is totally fine with me.
バカな貴様との契約が　まっこと心良いぞ
The river.
河 だな
Can you see what is happening, Lancer?
何が起こっているか見えますか　ランサー
It's Caster, all right.
やはリキャスターです　河の中に陣取って何かやっているらしい
He has taken position on the river
and appears to be doing something.
I cannot make out the details, however.
子細なところまでは見えかねますが
This would be the perfect opportunity to defeat him.
仕留めるなら　今が絶好のチャンスね
Indeed.
然り
If we defeat Caster,
キャスターを仕留めれば　一つ失ったランサーとの絆を取り戻せる
I can regain one of my bonds with Lancer that I had lost.
I will go engage him.
私は討って出ますが　ソラウ様はどうかここに居残り
Sola-Ui-sama, please stay here and bear witness to my deeds.
我が武功をご検分くださいますよう
What?!
そんな　私だって今はマスターです　お側から援護します
I'm your Master now! I'll assist you by your side.
You mustn't.
なりません　貴女にはケイネス殿のように武の心得があるわけではない
You don't understand matters of battle like Lord Kayneth did.
That river will become a land of death.
あの河岸は死地となりましょう　ご理解ください
Please understand.
But...
でも…
それとも　ソラウ様もまた
Sola-Ui-sama, do you suspect that the
tip of my spear is still shrouded in doubt?
このディルムッドの矛先に曇りありと疑われますか
That I would selfishly fool around in battle?
恣意なる戦いに戯れるものと
Lancer, I leave all field decisions to you.
ランサー　現場の判断はすべて貴方に任せます
May you fight freely with no regrets.
どうか存分に　悔いなき戦いを
I am in your debt.
忝ない
Should you return victorious...
勝利の暁には
Lancer, please show me your smile.
ランサー　貴方の笑顔を　私に
Caster...
キャスター
It's clear from this incredible outpouring of mana
that Caster is performing magic of an enormous scale.
キャスターが何らかの大規模魔術を遂行中であることは
この尋常ならざる魔力の放射から 疑う余地はありません
ようこそ聖処女よ
Welcome, Holy Virgin.
I am overjoyed that we can meet again.
再びお目にかかれたのは恐悦の至り
性懲りもなく 外道め
You never learn, fiend!
今夜は何を仕出かすつもりだ
What are you trying to do tonight?!
I'm terribly sorry, Jeanne.
申し訳ないがジャンヌ
You're not the guest of honor tonight.
今宵の主賓は貴女ではない
But if you would like to join us as well, I could have no greater happiness.
ですが 貴女もまた列席していただけるというのなら
私としては至上の喜びですとも
At this banquet of death and decadence that I, the humble Gilles de Rais, have prepared, everyone may eat their fill!
不肖ジル·ド·レェめが催す死と退廃の饗宴を
どうか心ゆくまで満喫されますよう
Now let us once again raise the flag of salvation!
今再び　我らは救世の旗を掲げよう
Caster is being absorbed?!
キャスターが吸収されていく
Gather here, O abandoned ones.
見捨てられたる者は集うがいい
I shall lead you! I shall command you!
私が率いる 私が統べる
The deep resentment that we, the
oppressed, hold shall reach God himself!
我ら貶められたる者たちの怨嗟は
必ずや神にも届く
O God in heaven, with words of
condemnation I praise your holy name!
おお天上の主よ
私は糾弾をもって御身を讃えよう
That's...
あれは
Arrogant God!
傲岸なる神を 冷酷なる神を
Cruel God!
我らは御座より引きずり下ろす
We shall pull you down from your throne.
Hey, King of Knights.
よお 騎士王
King of Conquerors...
征服王
Don't even start.
よせよせ 今夜ばかりは休戦だ
It's a truce tonight.
We can't fight each other in peace
unless we deal with that big thing first.
あんなデカブツをほっぽったままでは
おちおち殺し合いのひとつも出来ゃせんわ
I've been going around and telling everyone.
さっきから そう呼びかけて廻っとるのだ
ランサーは承諾した
Lancer agreed. He should be here soon.
じきに追いついてくるはずだ
了解した こちらも共闘に異存はない
Understood. We agree to fighting with you as well.
King of Conquerors, it will be a short alliance, but I swear loyalty to our common cause.
征服王 しばしの盟だが ともに忠を誓おう
Einzbern, you guys got a plan?
アインツベルン  あんたたちに策は
Lancer told me this isn't your first time fighting Caster.
さっきランサーから聞いたが
キャスター本人と戦うのはこれが最初じゃないんだろ
We need to defeat him as soon as we can.
ともかく速攻で倒すしかないわ
That monster is still maintaining itself in this world with Caster's mana.
あの怪物は 今はまだキャスターからの魔力供給で現界を保っているんだろうけれど
But it'll be too late once it gets its own
food source and becomes self-sufficient.
あれが独自に糧を得て自給自足を始めたら もう手に負えない
We need to stop Caster before that.
そうなる前にキャスターを止めなくては
I see.
なるほどな
So we need to settle this before it
reaches the coast and starts eating.
奴が岸に上がって食事をおっ始める前にケリをつけなきゃならんわけだ
But Caster himself is deep inside those thick walls of flesh.
しかし 当のキャスターはあの分厚い肉の奥底ときた
さて どうする
What do we do?
Drag him out.
引きずり出す
That's the only way.
それしかあるまい
If we can expose his Noble Phantasm, then my Gae Dearg can destroy the spell in one strike.
奴の宝具さえ剥き出しにできれば
俺の「破魔の紅薔薇」は一撃で術式を破壊できる
Lancer, will you be able to hurl your spear
and hit his Noble Phantasm from the coast?
ランサー その槍の投撃で 岸からキャスターの宝具を狙えるか
モノさえ見えてしまえば 雑作もないさ
It'll be no trouble if I can just see it.
ならば先鋒は私とライダーが務める
Rider and I will take the vanguard, then.
Is that fine, King of Conquerors?
いいな 征服王
I don't mind, but while my chariot needs no roads...
構わんが 余の戦車に路は要らぬから良いとしても
Saber, how will you attack the enemy in the river?
セイバー 貴様は河の中の敵をどう攻める気だ
I am under the protection of the Lady of the Lake.
この身は湖の乙女より加護を授かっている
No body of water can stop me, no matter how wide or deep.
何尋の水であろうとも我が歩みを阻むことはない
That's another rare skill to have.
それはまた希有な奴
I want you for my army even more now.
ますます我が幕下に加えたくなったのう
You'll pay for that remark later.
放言のツケはいずれまた払ってもらう
今はまず あの化け物の腑からキャスターを暴き出すのが先決だ
For now, it's imperative that we drag Caster out from inside that monster.
Indeed!
然り
Then I shall be the first to strike!
ならば一番槍は戴くぞ
Good luck, Saber.
セイバー 武運を
Let's finish this, Caster!
決着をつけるぞ
キャスター
Episode 13
The Forbidden Banquet
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Omoide ni yorisoinagara
If I can find peace in my recollections
思い出に寄り添いながら
Omoide ni yorisoinagara
If I can find peace in my recollections
思い出に寄り添いながら
Kimi wo omoeru nara
While reminiscing about you
君を想えるなら
Kimi wo omoeru nara
While reminiscing about you
君を想えるなら
Itsumo minareteru madobe ni utsutta
I am all too familiar with the window reflection
いつも見慣れてる窓辺に映った
Itsumo minareteru madobe ni utsutta
I am all too familiar with the window reflection
いつも見慣れてる窓辺に映った
Sono hitomi wa ashita wo muite ita
Of your eyes that were gazing into the future
その瞳は明日を向いていた
Sono hitomi wa ashita wo muite ita
Of your eyes that were gazing into the future
その瞳は明日を向いていた
Ah sakaraenu sadame to shitte mo
Ah, even though I know there's no escaping this fate
あぁ 逆らえぬ運命と知っても
Ah sakaraenu sadame to shitte mo
Ah, even though I know there's no escaping this fate
あぁ 逆らえぬ運命と知っても
Kowakunai kokoro kara shinjite iru
I'm not afraid. I have faith from the bottom of my heart
怖くない 心から信じている
Kowakunai kokoro kara shinjite iru
I'm not afraid. I have faith from the bottom of my heart
怖くない 心から信じている
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Kimi to sugoshita akashi wa
Proof of the time I spent with you
君と過ごした証は
Kimi to sugoshita akashi wa
Proof of the time I spent with you
君と過ごした証は
Tashika ni koko ni aru
Is right here with me
確かにここにある
Tashika ni koko ni aru
Is right here with me
確かにここにある
Afuredasu kimochi wo
You've shown me what it means
溢れ出す気持ちを
Afuredasu kimochi wo
You've shown me what it means
溢れ出す気持ちを
Oshiete kureta kara
To have overflowing feelings
教えてくれたから
Oshiete kureta kara
To have overflowing feelings
教えてくれたから
Kono sekai ga nakunatte mo
Even if this world were to end
この世界がなくなっても
Kono sekai ga nakunatte mo
Even if this world were to end
この世界がなくなっても
Watashi wa soko ni iru
I'll be right by your side
私はそこにいる
Watashi wa soko ni iru
I'll be right by your side
私はそこにいる
Get 'em, Mister Bluebeard!
やっちまえ 青髭の旦那
A failure of these proportions is unprecedented.
このような失態は前代未聞
You want me to draw my greatest treasure, Ea, here?!
我が至宝たる「エア」をここで抜けと
Saber!
セイバー
英雄王 どうかお待ちを
King of Heroes, please wait!
なんて奴だ
He's unbelievable.
一人残らず殺し尽くす
Kill all of them! Every last one!
Season
Begins April 2012